# Jason S.C, Yong Sheng NG

Mobile: +65 91371842

Skype: <u>jasonscourge@hotmail.com</u> Email: <u>nys@u.nus.edu</u>

Website: https://jasonscourge.github.io/WebsiteSV/

## **Personal Statement**

#### **About Me**

I am a 3<sup>rd</sup>-year Computer Science undergraduate at the National University of Singapore. I entered the world of Infocommunications Technology for fun about 10 years ago and have since developed a deep passion for it. I often enjoy working on my own hobbyist projects, many of which involve creating computer games, videos and web development.

#### **Work Experience**

My first working experience was at the Ministry of Education as an assistant Infocomn Trainer for a span of a year, where I learned and trained students to learn and use various multimedia software and basic programming. During the one year of development, I learned a great deal of media editing skills, UI/UX designs and web development. Additionally, I get to learn various soft skills such as communicating and interacting with young teenagers and adults alike in which it had lead me to know and eventually intern under the company known as Anteractif. From there, I took on the role as an assistant producer where I got to interact and work with clients in designing and development of websites and videos, from their ideation to its creation.

My internship at Togoparts had allowed me to further hone my skills in web development and increased my exposure to ecommerce technology. At Togoparts, I built an ecommerce web application for the company for their internal and public use. During my time there, I go the opportunity to learn various ecommerce frameworks, deploy and manage web services. Furthermore, I got the opportunity to work with a team with diverse backgrounds which allowed me to learn and improve my programming and design skills.

## **Objectives**

I hope that during my internship, I will be able to expose myself to new challenges and refine my skills further in software development and design. If time and chances permit, I would like to experiment new ideas and perspectives. Additionally, I am looking forward to learning and experiencing the challenges and joys in a start-up environment.

#### **Skills and Contributions**

I have experience in deploying and managing websites before and have knowledge with the UNIX command line. In addition, I have experience in deploying several test-run websites before using platforms before such as FastComet and Amazon Web Services. I also have a keen interest in UI/UX and Human Computer Interaction (HCI) and have taken several modules in them.

Furthermore, I have experience in both working and leading in game development and software engineering teams, particularly the latter in my university's software engineering module. I also have joined a plethora of hackathons and competitions and created of several apps and videos. Additionally, having experiences in public speaking, I was the presenter of my team and pitched our works to the public and judges. That has lead us to win several awards in which can be seen in the links shown in Appendix A.

In addition, I do spend free time in designing and creating various apps and games, in which throughout this process, I learn various coding and scripting languages and design skills between a computer and a human as well as various software nuances. Recently, I have been tinkering with old computers and a Raspberry Pi to set up and host web servers for my own custom web projects and I believe that this will further hone my web development skills.

Lastly, I am a swift and adaptable learner that can pick up new programming languages, frameworks and software skills quickly, which I believe is an essential skill in the everchanging landscape of software and app development. Furthermore, it is the core computer science principles that matter, regardless of programming language or environment.

## **Education**

Jan 2010 - Dec 2012

## **National University of Singapore**

Singapore

Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

(Relevant details in Appendix A)

## **Work Experience**

Jan 2010 - Jan 2012

#### **Ministry of Education**

Assistant Infocomn Trainer

- Coached students of various high schools in media production which eventually lead them to win several competitions
- Apprenticed under a professional trainer in the media industry to develop a comprehensive syllabus suitable for both to teenagers and adults

Feb 2012 - Dec 2013

## **Anteractif Pte Ltd**

Assistant Producer Intern

- Assisted with developing and designing various multimedia solutions for corporate companies
- Storyboarding and video production work for clients such as World Toilet Organization (WTO) and Mediacorp

Jun 2015 - Aug 2016

## **Speech Academy Asia**

Speech Trainer Trainee

- Trained by a professional trainer to teach aspiring young entrepreneurs and children on how to do public speaking in front of large crowds
- Also trained budding entrepreneurs together with fellow colleagues on how to market and do public speaking at the United Nations Women's 'Project Inspire'.

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

## **Togoparts Pte Ltd**

Web Developer Intern

- Constructed an e-commerce platform that allows the various affiliated vendors to have a guided autonomy in handling the sales and records of their products
- Used HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and an ecommerce framework

# **Achievements/Personal Projects**

Hero As A Hobby

A 3D third-person view game that incorporates Hack N' Slash and Shooting elements

- Won 1<sup>st</sup> place in Apollo 11 (Advanced Level) in Orbital 2016
- Won Certificate of Commendation in 9th STePs

Moonchaser

An Android platformer game created during a game hackathon event

• Won 1st place in the hackathon, Gamecraft 2016

Statement

A prototype made for Android phones that tackles the issue of indecisiveness of deciding what to wear amongst youngsters

• Won 1st runner up in 10th STePs under the UI/UX category

**Tone Dead Matrix** 

A tone matrix music software created for fun during HackfestSG hackathon

Die Popup!

A unique Android game created together with a group of friends with similar interests

**Run Wolf Run!** 

An Android platformer game created during DBS GameJam hackathon

[Links about the apps and games can be found below in Appendix A]

## **Extracurricular Activities**

Aug 2016 - Sep 2016 Singapore Geospatial Challenge Business Analytics Mania (SGCBAM) Singapore Emcee & Program Host Hosted and emcee for SGCBAM hackathon in 2016 Over a hundred audiences including ministers and industrial leaders Aug 2015 - Jul 2016 Singapore **National University of Singapore** Varsity Canoe Polo Player A sports game that involves canoeing, ball handling, excellent teamwork and communication to play Played in the varsity team and represented the school in various competitions such as National Championships Language Proficiency Spoken English - Fluent Written English - Advanced Mandarin - Fluent Mandarin - Intermediate Skill Sets & Proficiency **Proficient Programming** Java C++Intermediate C# Intermediate C Basic **Web Development HTML** Proficient **CSS** Intermediate Basic **iQuery** JavaScript Basic D3 Basic PHP Basic **AWS Basic Proficient** Frameworks & Engines Unity **Proficient** CS-Cart OpenGL Baisc Basic **Bootstrap** Basic Magento **Version Control Tools** Git Intermediate **Server Management** Web Server Setup & Maintenance Basic **Multimedia & Prototyping** Adobe Photoshop Advanced Balsmig Advanced Adobe Premire Pro **Proficient** Adobe After Effects Proficient Adobe Illustrator/Freehand **Proficient** Adobe Flash Intermediate MarvelApp Intermediate Axure RP Basic

Videography (Pre-production and Post-production)

Photography

Writing & Publications

**Others** 

Proficient

**Proficient** 

Basic

# Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

Objectives	Course Description
Computing	PROGRAMMING METHODOLOGY
	DISCRETE STRUCTURES
	CALCULUS FOR COMPUTING
	COMPUTING AND SOCIETY
	DATA STRUCTURES AND ALGORITHMS I
	DATA STRUCTURES AND ALGORITHMS II
	SOFTWARE ENGINEERING
	INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER NETWORKS
	DESIGN AND ANALYSIS OF ALGORITHMS
UI/UX	INTERACTION DESIGN
	PHENOMENA AND THEORIES OF HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION
Graphics and Games	COMPUTER GRAPHICS
	INDEPENDENT WORK
	REAL-TIME GRAPHICS
	GAME DESIGN
Communications	PUBLIC SPEAKING AND CRITICAL REASONING
	EFFECTIVE COMMUNICATION FOR COMPUTING PROFESSIONALS
	GLOBALISATION AND NEW MEDIA
	CRITICAL THINKING IN THE INFORMATION AGE

# Links

Prototypes and Apps Statement Tone Dead Matrix Do-er List	https://github.com/qroll/Statement/releases/download/v0.1.5/statement.apk https://jasonscourge.github.io/ToneDeadMatrix/ https://tinyurl.com/y7jf4kyd
Games Hero As A Hobby Moonchaser Die Popup! Run Wolf Run!	http://gamejolt.com/games/hero-as-a-hobby/215221 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.Company.MoonChaser&hl=en https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.Company.DiePopup&hl=en https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AxYM4Cb-vG4
Testimonial Togoparts	https://www.dropbox.com/s/tatvedkuk565ofg/togoparts_testimonial.pdf?dl=0
Others Github	https://github.com/JasonScourge

Jason S.C, Yong Sheng NG